<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright 2014 Ryan Lerch <rlerch@redhat.com> -->
<!-- Copyright 2016 Tim Kosse <tim.kosse@filezilla-project.org> -->
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>org.filezillaproject.Filezilla</id>
  <name>FileZilla</name>
  <summary>FileZilla Client is a fast and reliable cross-platform FTP, FTPS and SFTP client with lots of useful features and an intuitive graphical user interface</summary>
  <project_license>GPL-2.0-or-later</project_license>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <description>
    <p>FileZilla is a graphical FTP, FTPS and SFTP client. It is platform independent and supports all major desktop operating systems.</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Easy to use</li>
      <li>Supports FTP, FTP over SSL/TLS (FTPS) and SSH File Transfer Protocol (SFTP)</li>
      <li>Cross-platform. Runs on Windows, Linux, *BSD, OSX and more</li>
      <li>IPv6 support</li>
      <li>Available in many languages</li>
      <li>Supports resume and transfer of large files &gt;4GB</li>
      <li>Powerful Site Manager and transfer queue</li>
      <li>Bookmark</li>
      <li>Drag and drop support</li>
      <li>Configurable Speed limits</li>
      <li>Filename filters</li>
      <li>Directory Comparison</li>
      <li>Network configuration wizard</li>
      <li>The ability to use Notepad or any other program to edit a file online</li>
      <li>HTTP/1.1, SOCKS5 and FTP Proxy support</li>
      <li>Logging to file</li>
      <li>Synchronized directory browsing</li>
      <li>Remote file search</li>
    </ul>
  </description>
  <releases>
      <release version="3.46.0" date="2019-11-26">
        <description>
          <ul>
            <li>    Show an error message in the local directory listing if the user lacks permission to show the directory</li>
          </ul>
        </description>
      </release>
      <release version="3.45.1" date="2019-09-25">
        <description>
          <ul>
            <li>Minor performance improvements deleting many thousands of files</li>
            <li>Fixed prefix search in Site Manager</li>
            <li>Performance improvements if expanding or refreshing a directory with thousands of direct subdirectories in the directory trees</li>
          </ul>
        </description>
      </release>
      <release version="3.44.2" date="2019-08-15">
        <description>
          <ul>
            <li>Fixes to protocol selection glitches in the Site Manager</li>
            <li>Increase maximum length of response lines when using FTP</li>
          </ul>
        </description>
      </release>
      <release version="3.44.1" date="2019-08-09">
        <description>
          <ul>
            <li>Multiple items can now be selected in the Site Manager.</li>
            <li>Pressing F3 in the Site Manager opens a search dialog.</li>
            <li>Add a reminder to the message log to switch to FTP over TLS each time a plain FTP connection is used.</li>
          </ul>
        </description>
      </release>
      <release version="3.43.0" date="2019-06-27">
        <description>
          <ul>
            <li>Filenames containing double-quotation marks were not escaped correctly when selected for opening/editing. Depending on the associated program, parts of the filename could be interpreted as commands.</li>
            <li>Added a second layer of authentication to the update mechanism</li>
          </ul>
        </description>
      </release>
      <release version="3.42.1" date="2019-05-08">
        <description>
          <ul>
            <li>Fixed a potential crash if the first-launch welcome dialog is shown at an inopportune moment</li>
            <li>Fixed display of subject and issuer details in the certificate verification dialogs with some certificates</li>
          </ul>
        </description>
      </release>
      <release version="3.41.2" date="2019-03-18">
        <description>
          <ul>
            <li>Backport a security fix from PuTTY 0.71 affecting SFTP connections.</li>
          </ul>
        </description>
      </release>
      <release version="3.41.1" date="2019-03-06">
      <description>
        <ul>
		      <li>Fix a regression introduced in 3.41.1 with slow FTP servers needlessly waiting for a bidirectional shutdown of the data connection during downloads</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.41.0" date="2019-03-06">
      <description>
        <ul>
		      <li>Fixed crash if adding a bookmark with the current connection not yet having a Site Manager entry</li>
	      	<li>Fixed a rare crash if closing FileZilla while a recursive chmod operation is still in progress</li>
          <li>Fixed a rare crash if starting directory comparison on an empty directory without logical parent</li>
          <li>Fixed a rare crash on changing the file list sort order when the focused item index has previously become invalid</li>
          <li>Restrict the maximum length of regular expressions in filter conditions due to bugs in some implementations of the C++ Standard Library causing crashes</li>
          <li>Fixed order in which directories helper tools and data files are searched for</li>
          <li>Fixed a rare crash if closing tab during an ongoing recursive directory deletion</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.40.0" date="2019-01-25">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Refactored how sites and servers are being represented internally to fix issues trigged by renaming sites in the Site Manager</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.39.0" date="2018-11-30">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix timestamps of newly created empty files on the server if the option to preserve timestamps is set</li>
          <li>The down button on the keyboard now opens the quickconnect history dropdown menu if the quickconnect bar has the input focus</li>
          <li>The down button on the keyboard now opens the search options if the quick search dialog has the input focus</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.38.1" date="2018-10-27">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed crash if transferring three or more files in parallel when speed limits are enabled</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.38.0" date="2018-10-26">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Updated translations</li>
          <li>Refreshing remote file list while holding Ctrl now clears the remote directory cache for the current server</li>
          <li>Changed default logon type if creating a new site in the Site Manager</li>
          <li>Fixed state of controls in the Site Manager when creating a new site after the previously viewed site has been predefined</li>
          <li>Fixed dragging remote files to queue</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.37.4" date="2018-10-04"/>
    <release version="3.37.3" date="2018-09-21">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix issues with directory creation when uploading many files in parallel</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
  <url type="homepage">https://filezilla-project.org/</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://trac.filezilla-project.org/</url>
  <url type="faq">https://wiki.filezilla-project.org/FAQ</url>
  <url type="help">https://filezilla-project.org/support.php</url>
  <url type="translate">https://filezilla-project.org/translations.php</url>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">org.filezillaproject.Filezilla.desktop</launchable>
  <provides>
    <id>org.filezilla-project.FileZilla</id>
    <id>filezilla.desktop</id>
  </provides>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/flathub/org.filezillaproject.Filezilla/master/screenshot.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />
  <update_contact>tim.kosse@filezilla-project.org</update_contact>
</component>
